# Eric Mauldin

- Web Developer -

tel: 706.372.1536

email: emauldin84@gmail.com portfolio: ericmauldin.info

LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/ericmauldin</u> GitHub: github.com/emauldin84

Creative software engineer with the ability to pick up new languages and technologies as needed. Prior to being a software developer, I worked as a director of transportation for an Atlanta Destination Management Company where I managed complex logistics programs for Fortune 500s visiting the Atlanta area, providing clients with support and consultation for their specific needs.

### **EXPERIENCE**

# Immersive Full-Stack Web Developer Coding Bootcamp

DigitalCrafts, Atlanta, GA | Feb. 2019-May 2019

- 16-week, hands-on software development program covering HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, React, Redux, and AWS. My DigitalCrafts projects include:
- **Flamingo** <u>flamingo.ericmauldin.info</u> team project React, Node.js full stack web application utilizing Express, PostgreSQL, Vanilla JavaScript, Materialize, CSS, Axios. Flamingo is a mobilefirst, digital interpretation of a familiar way of showing trips across the globe. Users can quickly add, delete and edit past and future trips, creating and saving travel experiences.
- **C's Recipes** <u>cs-recipes.ericmauldin.info</u> A personal React project built out of my fiancée's need to manage her recipes. The idea was to build a simple interface to allow the user to add, search, view, edit and delete recipes. The backend is built using node and express accessing a PostgreSQL database.
- **MovieCloud** moviecloud.ericmauldin.info team project front-end web application built with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, REST API. Fetches API data from Open Weather Map, GraceNote Developer showtime API and OMDB Movie API to return the first rainy day (within five days) and all of the theaters and showtimes within a provided zip code.

## **Director of Transportation**

Presenting Atlanta, Atlanta, GA | Sept. 2011–Feb. 2019

- Coordinated complex transportation programs for Fortune 500s
- Consulted clients and Presenting Atlanta's sales team concerning all transportation needs
- Managed and curated a team of 20+ independent contractor staff as well as third party vendors
- Employed precise attention to detail to ensure programs were executed flawlessly and profitably from conception to completion
- Championed efficiency by designing and implementing new productivity tools to simplify and expedite logistics processes

### **SKILLS**

- · JavaScript, Node.js, HTML, CSS
- React, Express, Bootstrap
- PostgreSQL
- Git, GitHub, VS Code, Postman, AWS, EC2, Chrome Dev Tools, REST APIs
- WordPress
- QuickBooks

#### SIDE PROJECTS

#### Creator

BreakerOneNine | Oct. 2016-Oct. 2019

- Created and constructed the CDL employment site, breakeronenine.com
- Collaborated with professional development team for complex site customization

#### Co-Founder

Club Work | Aug. 2013-Mar. 2015

- Managed launch of online job board, clubwork.com
- Co-created a concise, inclusive and refined recruitment and placement system for matching Private Clubs with experienced prospective employees
- Worked conjointly with a local marketing and web development agency to optimize SEO and conversion rates within the Google AdWords and WordPress platforms

### **EDUCATION**

**BBA Management**, Terry College of Business

University of Georgia, Athens, GA | Aug. 2003-May 2008

Coursework focused on Operations management, Organizational behavior, and Strategic management